Connor Nicholls

1000 Spring Loop #1307, College Station, TX, 77840

818-577-9479 | CRNicholls20@tamu.edu | www.linkedin.com/in/connor-nicholls/ | fairo20.github.io

Objective

Looking to apply my several years of experience to research and internship opportunities in the field of embedded systems, software engineering, and game design.

Skills & Abilities

I have extensive experience in both C++ and Java, and have been working in embedded systems projects in both since 2013. I worked with basic mechanical systems through VEX robotics until 2016, when I joined an FRC team and gained experience with scheduled command-based structures, and I am currently a member of the Autonomous Vehicles lab under the supervision of Dr. Xingyong Song. In addition, I have managed projects such as the aforementioned programming team and other special projects from 2016-2020, and I am currently the Embedded Systems Lead of the TAMU Aimbots team, which competes in combat robotics and Robomasters. A list of previous projects and more information on my history can be found on my website, fairo20.github.io.

Experience

Executive VP of Integrations / Lead of Programming Team 1138 Eagle Engineering

August 2018 — May 2020

I managed programming and electrical projects and their integrations, which included oversight of a large codebase, git and scrum utilization, and experience with C++, Java, Python, CAD, CAN, and basic motor and motor controller functions

TAMU Aimbots Embedded Systems Team TAMU Robomasters

August 2020 - Present

I completed projects in scheduled and looped robot codebases, which included understanding of low-level embedded systems programming with utilities such as KEIL and experience with C++, advanced motor and motor controller functions, control loops, and computer vision principles.

Education

Texas A&M University — Computer Science

Fall 2020 — Present

Insofar I have achieved a GPA of 3.82, and have received the Engineering Dean's Honor Roll in Fall 2020, Fall 2021, and Spring 2022.

Leadership

I served as the Lead of Programming for Robotics Team 1138 Eagle Engineering from 2018-2019 and as the Executive Vice President of Integrations from 2019-2020, which entailed directing and managing all non-mechanical projects and personnel. I am currently serving as the Embedded Systems Lead of TAMU Aimbots, which involves project management, meeting coordination, and team direction over the course of the year. I have served on the leadership board of the Aggie Society of Anime and Manga Art as the IT Director for the club, which includes managing events, creating YouTube and streaming content, and maintaining an active Discord community.